Paul Harrington

Junior Full Stack Web Developer

Address: 1B Edenmore Grove Website: loosenthedark.tech

Dublin 5 Email: hello@loosenthedark.tech

Ireland LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/paulharrington05

Telephone: +353 894546613 GitHub: github.com/loosenthedark

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Passionate, detail-oriented Developer with experience in building elegant and engaging websites and applications. Emphasis on Frontend languages (HTML, CSS, JavaScript) and frameworks/libraries (Bootstrap, jQuery) combined with a strong grasp of Backend programming (Python+Flask) and database management systems (MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB). A skilled problem-solver and constant learner, I pride myself on delivering a first-rate user experience with every project.

RECENT PROJECTS

2016:

Clipadvisor Data-centric SaaS application with full CRUD functionality, enabling users

to post, view, edit and delete reviews of barbers (README)

StrikeForce Interactive Frontend website leveraging an external API to create incisive

data visualisations of English Premier League goalscoring trends (README)

Matter of Heart Psychotherapy Bespoke responsive Frontend site for a local therapy practice (README)

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS

2020 - present:	Full Stack Diploma in Software Development at Code Institute	
	 Europe's only university credit-rated coding bootcamp 	

 Course developed in partnership with an Industry Advisory Council comprising key players such as Salesforce, PayPal, Accenture and GlaxoSmithKline

key players sach as salestoree, I ayr al, necentare and slaxosimentality

TEFL Graduate Certificate in Teaching English as a Foreign Language

IARC-accredited 150 Hour Master Course

Completed September 2016, achieving grade A

2013 - 2015: Higher Diploma in Psychology at Dublin Business School

Graduated November 2015 with First-Class Honours

QQI Level 8 programme accredited by the Psychological Society of Ireland

2000 - 2005: Bachelor of Arts (Joint Honours) Degree at University College Dublin

 Graduated October 2005 with First-Class Honours in French and Second-Class Honours (2:1) in Sociology

 Awarded the 2005 NUI/French Government Medal and NUI Prize for Proficiency in French

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

May 2018 - Oct 2020: English Tutor with SayABC (Horizon Education HK, Ltd.)

- Developed teaching materials to supplement standard curriculum, enhancing learning concepts and promoting student engagement.
- Mastered use of TPR, student reward systems and age-appropriate feedback to create a dynamic and immersive learning environment
- Maintained a consistently strong track record of being renewed, at parents' request, as a SayABC Homeroom Teacher

Dec 2016 - Aug 2018: English Tutor with TOPICA EdTech Group

- Gained advanced proficiency in using TOPICA Native's EdTech platform for remote teaching of group classes (available to adult learners throughout Vietnam, Thailand and Indonesia) at Beginner and Intermediate levels
- Planned and implemented lessons to increase vocabulary and sentence structure skills by actively encouraging student expression and interaction
- Received over 300 five-star ratings on the Student Feedback Board measuring students' satisfaction with Topica teachers – following its introduction in mid-2017

Nov 2016 - May 2018: English Teacher/Corporate Trainer with Language Express (LX)/Corporate Training Express (CTX), Bangkok

- Conducted a mix of classroom-based (LX) and remote client-tailored (CTX) lessons, ranging from private tutoring to overseeing groups of more than 50 students
- Catered to the evolving educational needs of corporate clients including EY Thailand, Hunton & Williams, Swatch Group and the Embassy of New Zealand
- Awarded the Language Express Teacher Training Certificate of Achievement (Ministry of Education-certified)
- National Children's Day 2017 Corporate Training Express Ambassador

Feb - Oct 2016:

Facilities Manager/Laboratory Attendant at UCD Medical Bureau of Road Safety

May - Nov 2015:

Psychology Intern with the International Association of Applied Psychology at **United Nations Headquarters, New York**

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- I like to supplement my core web development studies by exploring new and emerging technologies whenever I can. I recently learned PHP as part of Udemy's 'Complete Web Developer Course 2.0', and am currently improving my React skills through freeCodeCamp's just-released 'Code 15 React Projects' course.
- I also enjoy connecting with fellow tech enthusiasts via social media and business communication platforms (Twitter, LinkedIn, Slack), as well as "learning through building" by following video tutorial series and mini-projects from the likes of Frontend Mentor, Traversy Media, Wes Bos and Corey Schafer.
- Besides coding, I count travel as one of my main passions. My time spent travelling throughout Asia (China, India and Southeast Asia), as well as living in America (2015) and Thailand (2016-2018), has given me a rich appreciation of a number of different cultures and communication styles. I have also acquired many of the skills and resources necessary for remote working as a result of my more recent travels.